그래서, 이 작은 머신은 무엇과
비슷하게 보여지나요?
So, what does this little
machine look like?
기억을 상기해보자. 우리는 RNNs이 더 많은 것을
기억하는것을 돕기 위한 것을 하고 있습니다.
Remember, we're doing this to help RNNs
memorize things better.
그래서, 잠시만 neural networks에
대한 것을 잊기로 하자.
So let's forget about neural
networks for just a moment.
당신은 기억을 가지고 있는 시스템을
원한다고 상상해보자.
Imagine that you want
a system to have memory.
당신은 세가지가 필요할 것이다.
You need to do three things.
첫번째로, 데이터를 메모리에 쓰는것이 필요하다.
First, you need to write
the data into the memory.
다시 읽기도 필요할 것이고,
Then you will be able to read it back,
and
데이터를 지우는 것도 원할 것이다.
then you also want to be
able to erase it, or forget.
여기에는 메모리에 쓰는 하나의 방법입니다.
그림과 같은 간단한 아이디어입니다.
Here is one way to write this
very same idea down as a diagram.
당신은 메모리를 가지고 있고,
메모리에는 아마도 행렬값입니다.
You have a memory,
which is maybe a matrix of values.
당신은 메모리로 들어가는 입력값과
작은 명령어를 가지고 있습니다.
You also have inputs coming into
the memory, and a little instruction
gate는 입력값을 쓸지 그렇지 않을지를 알려줍니다.
gate that tells whether you are going
to write to that memory or not.
당신은 또한 다른 gate을 가지고 있으며,
You also have another gate that's
그것은 메모리로부터 읽어올지 그렇지 않을지를 알려줍니다.
says whether you are going to able
to read from that memory or not.
그리고 마지막 gate는 데이터를 잊을지
또는 다시 쓸지를 알려줍니다.
And then you have one final gate that
says forget the data or write it back.